<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meta on Passing thoughts</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/meta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meta on Passing thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Slow Productivity: some book notes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2024-04-27-Slow-Productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2024-04-27-Slow-Productivity/</guid>
      <description>1 American authors sometimes forget for many people the dream is to emigrate to somewhere like America. This is a very different kind of ambition from being &amp;ldquo;So Good They Can’t Ignore You&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;2 Do we have to be very &amp;ldquo;successful&amp;rdquo; in the first place? In the sense of being better by a significant than others on some objective measure? Surely not, even though that is the inevitable premise of self-help.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ask Your Developer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2024-04-01-AskYourDeveloper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2024-04-01-AskYourDeveloper/</guid>
      <description>Ask Your Developer is Twilio co-founder Jeff Lawson’s advice to Businesses looking to survive and prosper in the digital age. In short, Jeff argues that:&#xA;(1) Businesses need to embrace technology (esp. web technology) to compete;&#xA;(2) Rather than buying them ready-made (e.g. from a consultancy), businesses do better by buying “software parts” and assemble a custom solution. For example, Twilio excels at providing tools for integrating mobile phone text-messaging to software programmes; Cloudfare specialises in protection from DDOS attacks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can someone tinker her way into programming in the 2020s?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2024-03-23-Tinkering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2024-03-23-Tinkering/</guid>
      <description>My answer is no. The attention economy has closed off a route that was available as recently as a decade ago.&#xA;Background: I came across an unusually patient and helpful answer by adsy on StackOverflow, which led me to this article.&#xA;After reading it, it struck me that the way people first experience computers and programming has transformed in the last 20 years.&#xA;adsy got into programming the early 2000s. The dot-com bubble had burst.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing Jekyll on a Mac in March 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2024-03-23-Installing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2024-03-23-Installing/</guid>
      <description>Why&#xA;I wanted to run Jekyll on my Mac to see changes locally. Process&#xA;Follow the quickstart guide on official Jekyll website&#xA;Problem 1: gem install jekyll received no output.&#xA;Solution: terminal helpfully warned that.&#xA;You don&amp;rsquo;t have /Users/username/.gem/ruby/2.6.0/bin in your PATH, gem executables will not run.&#xA;Problem 2: find the PATH&#xA;Solution: (a) echo @$PATH``, (b) edit .bash_profile```&#xA;Problem 3: still no Jekyll&#xA;Use the which command to find out why Jekyll isn&amp;rsquo;t recognised</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting up the blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2024-03-21-SettingUp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 14:04:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2024-03-21-SettingUp/</guid>
      <description>This website was set up by following this helpful tutorial.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
